

# **DANIEL ANDRUS**

Phone: (605) 269-1728 Email: danieleandrus@gmail.com Twitter Handle: @deaboy100 Github Name: Deaboy

## **PROFILE**

I have a passion for video games and technology, and my career goal is to become a software engineer in the games industry, the mobile application industry, or the desktop application industry. I grew up in La Crescenta, California before moving to South Dakota in Summer, 2010. I attended Black Hills State University for two years before transferring to South Dakota School of Mines and Technology where I graduated with a **Bachelors Degree of Computer Science** in May, 2016. I went on to compete in the **ACM-ICPC World Finals** in Phuket, Thailand and afterward began my career as a software engineer at **Google Inc**. Currently I am located in **San Bruno**, **California** where I work on the Android YouTube app.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEER, GOOGLE INC — JUNE 2016 - PRESENT**

I began my career as a **Software Engineer at Google Inc**. I specifically worked on the **YouTube app** on Android and worked closely with **Android OS**. My roles included working closely and collaboratively with the other team members to meet goals and create maintainable software systems.

#### INTERN DEVELOPER, 7400 CIRCUITS — MAY 2015 - DECEMBER 2015

I held an internship at 7400 Circuits, a circuit board company located in Rapid City. Here I worked to improve an existing an **iOS and Android game** called *Trouble with Robots*. I also worked on a **cross-platform desktop application** that interacted via USB with a handheld game cartridge reader and writer that allows users to create and play Neo Geo Pocket and WonderSwan games on their handheld game devices.

#### SDSM&T PROGRAMMING TEAM — SEPTEMBER 2014 - JUNE 2016

In fall 2014, I joined the SDSMT programming team and participated in the ACM regional Programming Competition where my team finished 14th in the region out of over 285 competing teams and 1st in the school. In fall 2016, my team qualified for the **ACM-ICPC World Finals** and travelled to Phuket, Thailand in May 2016 to participate.

#### **SERVER ADMINISTRATOR, PROGRAMMER** — 2010 - 2015

Since 2010, I have owned and operated a public game server for which I and another developer have written hundreds of lines of **server software** to help manage the community. Through this, I have become greatly acquainted with **Linux**, **SSH**, and **managing small communities**.

## WEB DESIGNER AND DEVELOPER, BLACKHILLS.COM — 2013 - 2015

In May 2013, I started working for a local web development company as a full-time web developer. The job entailed **designing and building websites** of diverse sizes and varieties. Many sites were for small businesses located throughout the Black Hills, but a few were for large, high-traffic businesses such as BlackHillsNews.com and Sturgis.com.

#### **SKILLS**

- Programming in the Java, C, C++, C#, PHP, Lua, Python, Objective-C, and Swift programming languages.
- · OS X, iOS, Android, and web development.
- Working with web technologies, including HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP.
- Designing database systems using MySql.
- Working on team projects, object-oriented program design, and source control systems such as Git and Subversion.

#### **EDUCATION**

- General Studies Black Hills State University, Spearfish, SD 2010-2012
- B.S. of Computer Science South Dakota School of Mines and Technology, Rapid City, SD 2012-2016

### PERSONAL INFORMATION

I am good at math, am a fast learner, can pick up on new programming languages and standards quickly, and am a stickler for the proper usage of the word "literally". I can easily adapt to design patterns as well as programming paradigms and am perpetually learning the technologies and techniques employed in the software development, UX design, and game design industries.

In my spare time, I enjoy playing and creating video games, creating YouTube videos, and learning more about the everchanging technology industry. I love spending time with friends who enjoy similar things as I do. My career goals are to go into mobile application design and development, desktop application design and development, or game design and development. My ultimate personal goal with technology is to create applications that make people's lives better.